<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd"
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/">
  <channel>
    <title>prole.in</title>
    <link>http://prole.in/blog</link>
    <description>What the prole has been writing</description>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanical Reproduction in the Age of ART.haml</title>
      <link>http://localhost:9393/blog/Mechanical+Reproduction+in+the+Age+of+ART.haml</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;30 Jun 2010&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://koshtifertility.co.in/images/i0v0f.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;Some of my observations on the process of becoming parents in the industrial age. The names have been changed to protect the innocent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The effects of industrial society make themselves felt on the process of childbearing and parenting much before the actual process starts. Like everyone else, you have been swayed by the wonderfully modern concepts of &amp;#8220;freedom&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;convenience&amp;#8221; (and perhaps even a little bit of scorn for your old-fashioned parents) or even worse, a &amp;#8220;career&amp;#8221;, and have put off having a child until the very last minute. Having made all the calculations, you and your spouse have decided that you can now afford a child. It still of course depends on the stock market but hey, no one&amp;#8217;s getting any younger. Your biological clocks are ticking. Fresh with the optimism from this decision, you and your spouse embark on the most pleasurable activity of bay making. At last, not-so-young man, you can claim that elusive erotic privilege of ejaculating inside your wife, instead of in a plastic bag. You start. Taking out time and energy and enthusiasm for the act of lovemaking from the stresses of your daily lives, you start coupling with increased intensity. If you are lucky, it can work quite well. The shared mission brings you closer to your spouse and your marriage seems solid, your home a good one to bring a child into. However, if you are unlucky, and it seems &lt;a href=&quot;http://indiatoday.intoday.in/site/Story/102985/India/infertility-on-the-rise.html&quot;&gt;an increasing number are&lt;/a&gt;, then give thanks for all the other wonderful things that industrial society has kept in store for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To begin with, the mother-to-be finds that her body still inhabits an age when childbearing happened much sooner and by the mid-to-late thirties is now rife with fibroids or cysts or her tubes are malfunctioning or any number of such complications brought about by the passage of time, time spent in the pursuit of &amp;#8220;freedom&amp;#8221;, which in most cases might well have meant the freedom to work long hours and spend ones free time drunk in loud clubs or on the Internet. In any case, the first industrial intervention is necessitated here. Trips to the fertility clining, masturbation in a cup, painful needles poked up the vagina, dyes forced through the tubes and any number of other invasions of the body and the spirit and that is just the beginning. The act of love, performed so casually and unthinkingly in the millenia of human existence is now reduced to clock-watching and the rubbing of bodies at predetermined times and places. Ovulation times are determined. Meetings are scheduled around &amp;#8220;doing it&amp;#8221;. If work takes you out of town, get ready for all the recriminations attendant with prolonging this torture for another month. Careful attention is paid to each drop of semen, more valuable than gold. But not to worry, after extensive tests the problem is diagnosed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the problem is diagnosed, it is time for the treatment. If you are lucky it is something small which only takes a week to recover from. Advances in industrial medicine mean that only small cuts are necessitated. A camera is inserted into you and a skilled doctor removes the offending obstruction. Later, you can even watch a video of it with the helpful attendant augmenting your vocabulary with words like &amp;#8220;laparoscopic&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;fundus&amp;#8221;, etc. which you can toss around casually at cocktail parties if so inclined. A lakh plus is nothing. After all, you don&amp;#8217;t have much time. What good is the money if not for this, etc. etc. Eventually, after some more rubbing and clock-watching, the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;HCG&lt;/span&gt; report comes back and is within the pregnant range. Ecstasy! and then rapidly uncertainty and fear. You know this cousin&amp;#8217;s friend conceived at 36 and she had a miscarriage. My neighbour&amp;#8217;s wife has had two. Quick &amp;#8211; to the Internet. Google &amp;#8211; miscarriage rates in older mothers. Oh my God! 2% of people miscarry. Baby, that&amp;#8217;s nothing. It&amp;#8217;s not nothing. And so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The overriding emotion during the rest of the pregnancy is quite stark in its simplicity &amp;#8211; fear. Living as we do in nuclear families, the couple is essentially left to stew in their own anxieties. There is nobody there to assuage the fears. The older generation in any case feels perhaps vindicated in this situation. After all, they had been telling you all along to &amp;#8220;do things at the right time&amp;#8221;. Their advice now comes loaded always with the almost indistinguishable smirk of &amp;#8220;didn&amp;#8217;t we tell you so?&amp;#8221;. There are still some doctors left who go out of their way to calm the expectant couple and make their life easier, however one suspects that they are in the minority. After all, industrial medicine is a for-profit venture and there is no juicier mark than an older, affluent urban couple with a precious foetus. Game on! The couple, having been &amp;#8220;educated&amp;#8221; in the system, has already all the faith in &amp;#8220;modern technology&amp;#8221; and welcome the reassuring, if cold, embrace of modern medicine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, ultrasounds every two weeks, 6 week dating scan, 12 week anomaly scan, amniocentesis &amp;#8211; the list of interventions is laid out and well known. The risks are carefully delineated &amp;#8211; 1 in 465 women of your profile have a Downs syndrome baby and there is a 2% chance of miscarriage from amniocentesis. Choose! Of course, there is no choice. Capitalism is survival of the fittest. Industrial society has no place for idiots. Is there space in our careers for a spastic baby? When you get old, who will look after you? A mongoloid? But what if we miscarry? We can&amp;#8217;t go through this again. sweetheart, we can always adopt, but a Downs syndrome baby would be a catastrophic outcome. Come come, everything will be alright. At the 6 week dating scan a very serious looking ultrasonologist in front of a very serious machine &amp;#8211; 4d echo Doppler scan &amp;#8211; looks intently at the inside of the uterus and proclaims seriously &amp;#8211; subseptate. Google &amp;#8211; 2/3 chance of miscarriage. Stay in bed, the doctor advises, on your left side. Helpless, the mother lies stewing in her anxiety, laptop open to the various websites &amp;#8211; worry, don&amp;#8217;t worry. Worry. The good news is that the results came back from the amniocentesis &amp;#8211; there&amp;#8217;s only now a 0.5% chance of Downs syndrome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At around this time, the pretty young girls in the doctor&amp;#8217;s waiting room start approaching you. Would you like to store your baby&amp;#8217;s umbilical cord blood? It can be used to cure a number of diseases later (a lie). We will store it for 21 years. Spinal cord injuries? Why, yes sir, they can e cured (a lie). These are stem cells. They can cure anything (another lie). Of course, the unspoken undertone is that only a stingy bastard would deny his baby access to these wonderful life saving technologies. What is 70,000 bucks? We even have an installment plan. Asking the doctor yields this &amp;#8211; if you can afford it, go for it. But we heard it is banned in Europe? Roll of the eyes. You see, some of these business type families, you know uneducated, they don&amp;#8217;t go for it. Most couples like you&amp;#8230;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When all else fails, there is &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;IUGR&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#8211; the Intra Uterine Growth Restriction. Just a foetus and the baby is already being measured against a &amp;#8220;norm&amp;#8221;. Measurement is of course the cornerstone of the industrial method. Where this &amp;#8220;norm&amp;#8221; has come from is never revealed. What was the sample size, where was the sample taken from, are the actuarial tables from the US, have the machines been re-calibrated for India? Why answer these questions? A badly calibrated machine brings more revenue. Do you dare to question the wisdom of GE? Now that the baby is &amp;#8220;performing poorly&amp;#8221;, it is time for more scans. And oh, don&amp;#8217;t forget the supplements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual, the industrial method is providing, in its own way, answers to problems created by itself. The quality of those answers is poor, but the way they are delivered is so dazzling, those shiny chrome implements, those rounded plastic buttons, those screens and readouts, those scientific sounding words on paper, the backing of multinational corporations &amp;#8211; GE, Pfizer, Novartis&amp;#8230;.No one notices the ill effects of the industrial lifestyle, the lack of healthy and natural lifestyle options, the stress, the constant cocooning of the body for protection from the city, the lack of traditional support systems along with the death of traditional knowledge and the loss of control over ones own well-being and the crushing of the spirit under the machine-precision of modern science, most of which is as it turns out, totally fallible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end it turns out that there is no septum in the uterus, the misdiagnosis and subsequent confinement to the bed did more harm than good, the recovery from the unnecessary Cesarean operation was much more difficult, compounded by the atrophied musculature. The cost associated with these misdiagnoses of course get counted as in increase in &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;GDP&lt;/span&gt;. A simple home birth with a midwife and some boiling water wouldn&amp;#8217;t count you see. C&amp;#8217;mon young mother, take a scar across your midriff for the stock market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does this end with the birth of that little bundle of joy? That mewling infant that has been birthed under the cyclops glare of an operating theater lamp, amongst the cold steel of a modern birthing &amp;#8220;facility&amp;#8221;? Far from it, it is indeed just beginning. Characteristically, there is no one now to provide guidance as to nursing. In this entire process, the one thing that requires some knowledge i.e. the nursing process, a proper latch for the infant, etc. is completely disregarded. Then, when the baby loses some weight he gets sent to the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;NICU&lt;/span&gt;. Far be it from anyone to mention that all babies lose weight in the first few days. When a 6 pound baby becomes a 5.5 pound baby, he gets sent to the Neonatal intensive care unit where doctors stare at him gravely and monitor his charts and his temperature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new parents are never given time to enjoy this wonderful moment. The newborn screening tests are in and the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;IRT&lt;/span&gt; is slightly elevated. The paediatrician suspects cystic fibrosis. Before investigating the nursing, before taking some time to allow the baby to start gaining weight, before everything he suggests that the baby might have the cruel wasting disease that will see him dead by 20 and which the probability of him having is so vanishingly small as to be non-existent. Of course, the new parents are still not completely disillusioned with the industrial process and so spend more time worrying. The doctor has of course prescribed more tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it goes. Weighing, measuring, supplementing &amp;#8211; this is what passes for parenting in the industrial world. While he is an infant, he will be measured against some charts for height, weight and head circumference. Later, he will be graded against his ability to regurgitate a state mandated syllabus. Afterwards, he will be judged not only by the size of his bank account but by the conspicuous consumption he indulges in and by the banal conformity of his ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a detailed analysis of the ills of industrialization, do read &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.davidtinapple.com/illich/&quot;&gt;Ivan Illich&lt;/a&gt;. If you enjoyed this post, you might enjoy Illich&amp;#8217;s seminal &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.davidtinapple.com/illich/nemesis.html&quot;&gt;Medical Nemesis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2010 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2010-06-30T12:00:00+05:30</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Day.haml</title>
      <link>http://localhost:9393/blog/My+Day.haml</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Each morning same story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wake up. Cock an eye at the clock. &lt;br /&gt;
Panic, then realise its not late at all, close eyeszzz.z&amp;#8230;.zzz&amp;#8230;.. Open eyes, panic!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s late! Rush, rush, brush, flush. &lt;br /&gt;
Pack laptop, pop tap locks, take helmet and bike &lt;br /&gt;
  past fellows well met but who I don&amp;#8217;t like, &lt;br /&gt;
  out the door and into the street, &lt;br /&gt;
      automatic doors slide aside and &lt;br /&gt;
  introduce you to the heat.&lt;/p&gt;
H E A T.
&lt;p&gt;Murder by degrees as one rides, &lt;br /&gt;
  alert and watchful with eagle eyes &lt;br /&gt;
  and bat ears to hear the shush, &lt;br /&gt;
    the whispered breath &lt;br /&gt;
    of approaching death &lt;br /&gt;
  in the form &lt;br /&gt;
  of a mom &lt;br /&gt;
    and Huey, Dewey and Louie &lt;br /&gt;
    in a big fuckoff &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SUV&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;br /&gt;
keeping cool on the way to school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sandwiches and traffic jams, &lt;br /&gt;
  well behaved commuters mutter into cellphones that flip &lt;br /&gt;
    and clack back with a whack. &lt;br /&gt;
Fast talking radio show hosts &lt;br /&gt;
  honor the ghosts &lt;br /&gt;
    of the dead in Iraq. &lt;br /&gt;
  Bluetooths blip plaints and curses through thin air, &lt;br /&gt;
  the vapour pulses with despair. &lt;br /&gt;
A woman walks across the parking lot. &lt;br /&gt;
    She is black.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Off the road and cutting short &lt;br /&gt;
  through the parking lot &lt;br /&gt;
  of the Nassau Coliseum (sic). &lt;br /&gt;
Acres of tarmac with the odd car parked, &lt;br /&gt;
  baking, the arena with names not its own &lt;br /&gt;
  (but not on loan) &lt;br /&gt;
  shimmers in a grey and white-lined bleak heat. &lt;br /&gt;
  Freak street!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast cars blur &lt;br /&gt;
  the final curve, &lt;br /&gt;
the glass and steel mousewheel &lt;br /&gt;
  towers above. &lt;br /&gt;
  The office. Cool elevators serve rides and propaganda, &lt;br /&gt;
  dinging the floors to the top. &lt;br /&gt;
  Below, the freeway races non-stop, &lt;br /&gt;
    like bubbles in a pipe. &lt;br /&gt;
    Inside the blue light nothing seems right. &lt;br /&gt;
    I wish I could disappear, &lt;br /&gt;
    drop out of sight and just be by your side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And thats just how it starts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2010 09:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2010-06-30T09:00:00+05:30</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Population.haml</title>
      <link>http://localhost:9393/blog/Population.haml</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;14 Jun 2010&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;UPDATE&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;br /&gt;
Dissecting those Overpopulation Numbers&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://climateandcapitalism.com/?p=2270&quot;&gt;Part One: Population Where?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://climateandcapitalism.com/?p=2560&quot;&gt;Part Two: The Perils of Per Capita&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 Jun 2010&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://ramparts360.files.wordpress.com/2009/12/overpopulation-scales1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; The thing about population is that any statement you make about population is more a political statement than a statement of fact. The simple reason for this is that in reality, we have absolutely no fucking clue how many people there are on this fair planet of our&amp;#8217;s. Sometimes, when certain unverifiable facts are taken by the entire world to be almost self-evident, it might be useful to apply a little homegrown cynicism to these &amp;#8220;facts&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bulk of the world&amp;#8217;s people, it seems, live in India and China, some 2.5 odd billion people out of 6 or 7 billion on the whole planet. Do you seriously expect me to take these numbers at face value? Are you saying that our wonderful census department (and I suppose China&amp;#8217;s equally wonderful one) managed to count, to within a reasonably degree of accuracy, all these people by the simple expedient of sending out armies of poorly paid and unmotivated census takers? In India, it could be argued, there is significant incentive to manipulate the census numbers since electoral districts are based on population, as are other government handouts. I&amp;#8217;m not saying that UP does not have 200 million people. I&amp;#8217;m just saying that I don&amp;#8217;t know, and in fact, given the odds, I can be reasonably certain that any number you tell me has about equal chance of being close to the real number as it does of being totally off the fucking map.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, since we&amp;#8217;re now looking at the world through eyes innocent, what does it mean when says things like &amp;#8220;Overpopulation is the number one problem on earth.&amp;#8221; ? One of the things it could mean is that the speaker of this sentence is a genocidal fascist. I&amp;#8217;m speculating here but amongst the tonier drawing rooms on the subcontinent (where overpopulation is not someone else&amp;#8217;s problem you see, where you have the luxury of compassion. Here it is a very real problem, very real), the vision one gets when one thinks of overpopulation is of ragged people with no resources surrounded by fly infested children, dirtying the whole place, filling the slums and generally straining the infrastructure and public resources of what would otherwise be a country that one could show off proudly to the West. &lt;img src=&quot;http://isiria.files.wordpress.com/2009/01/overpopulation1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:right;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; This image can quite easily be seen from the window of any Mercedes in the suburbs of Mumbai, or experienced closely from the back seat of a rickshaw in any metropolis in India, and so it is not surprising that it springs so readily to mind. Neither is it surprising that people tend to place the blame on those unwashed, diseased people because after all anyone who shits on their own front step is clearly and quite obviously to blame in this depressing scene. Why, people like Atanu Dey who write tome after tome of hateful bile on India&amp;#8217;s development even go so far as to offer these people the helpful suggestion that they should stop having children because it ruins the aesthetics of his city. I have a suggestion for people like Atanu and others so concerned about overpopulation, perhaps even some people in the West who worry about the future of a world with 9 billion or 12 billion people. The suggestion is as follows&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why don&amp;#8217;t you chop your fucking head off?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all, the concern with overpopulation is a concern for the biosphere, for the Earth (our green and pristine paradise) who needs protecting from the people who will chop all her forests and poision her air and water. And so, where better to start with than the hyperconsumptive West, whose small populations hit way above their weight when it comes to raping the earth? One might also start in the tony neighbourhoods of Mumbai and Delhi, whose 2% or 3% of the Indian population is nonetheless responsible for almost all the resource exploitation in India. And carry on to the gated communities of Beijing and Melbourne and so on and so forth. Once these people are gone, overconsumption will no longer be a problem as the rest of the world seems to manage to still live a life consuming mostly vegetables and grains, using miniscule amounts of hydrocarbons and keeping their populations in check through a mature approach to illness, suffering and death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The explosion in the population of so-called &amp;#8220;poor people&amp;#8221; is mainly due to the industrial interventions for reducing mortality and fertility. Do you feel this was necessary? Do you feel that people in primitive or agrarian communities died from lack of preventable measures like washing hands after crapping or contamination of food and water sources from shitting willy nilly? You do? Congratulations &amp;#8211; you have an industrial mind. Do you feel that women were nothing but receptacles for sperm, constantly pregnant and ill and oppressed? Congratulations again. Could it be that I support these abominations? Actually, I do not. The thing I am skeptical about is the conviction that life was necessarily like that, and the conviction that logic, rationality and the industrial approach are necessarily superior to a mystical mind which seeks to accept its fate with fortitude rather than rail against it. Do check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://findarticles.com/p/articles/mi_m0ISW/is_2002_Jan/ai_81138280/?tag=content;col1&quot;&gt;Female Reproductive Health: An Anthropological Perspective&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you drive through UP in the baking heat of summer, you might see a sight that revolts the rational mind. A marriage celebration at midday, when the heat waves from the macadam distort the view and the heat will dry your eyes and the inside of your lungs. A marrige celebration with the band going full swing, little children dancing in the street (some of them barefoot) and a groom on a horse in a heavy bandgalla. It is a full blown celebration of community in such adverse circumstances that it is not logical, not rational, not at all. We industrial people drove by in our car, the airconditioner on full blast. The &amp;#8220;primitive&amp;#8221; village people seem to have perfected the art of not needing one. Heat, cold, rain &amp;#8211; they are all the same. They are all nothing. Am I an evil person who wants to deny the benefits of technology to the poor? I ask &amp;#8211; what benefits? The severe dependence on hyrocarbon use? The addiction to screens? The destruction of communities? The commodity fetish? In return for some temperature control which has quite evidently not been a problem for the vast majority of humans for millenia and continues to be so? In return for some speed which &lt;a href=&quot;https://clevercycles.com/energy_and_equity/&quot;&gt;creates more distances than it bridges&lt;/a&gt; ? In return for Deepwater Horizon? In return for the destruction of the awareness of the sacred and the sublime, the holy forests, the lakes and streams that are God incarnate? In return for such overweening complexity that every man has to be just a cog, a specialist in a huge machine rather than an agent of his own will? Damn right I am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, to return to our original point &amp;#8211; any statement about population is a political statement based as it is on some dubious &amp;#8220;facts&amp;#8221; and some very deep seated assumptions of right and wrong which in the end are moral choices and not objective facts like the weight of a hydrogen atom. To those who fear overpopulation, pray for an end to the populations of the developed world. The logical end point of industrialisation which promises leisure and comfort for all is an unattainable lie. Primitive people have long known that labour and rest, pleasure and pain, life and death, heat and cold are all part of one whole. Industrial societies all want to save labour, they see pain as something to be conquered, death as something to be delayed for as loing as possible, other people are inconveniences who prevent the full flowering of the individual. It is industrial society&amp;#8217;s inability to fill the spiritual holes it has created that leads to the statement &amp;#8211; the real problem facing the world is overpopulation. In other words, the world would be fine if it weren&amp;#8217;t for other people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a death wish.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2010 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2010-06-14T12:00:00+05:30</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inverting the Pyramid.haml</title>
      <link>http://localhost:9393/blog/Inverting+the+Pyramid.haml</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jun 9 2010&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://t1.gstatic.com/images?q=tbn:Xd0B0iG547SfAM:http://www.97thfloor.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2007/10/inverted-pyramid-1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; Today, a document arrived in my inbox with the charming title of &amp;#8220;Inverting the Pyramid&amp;#8221; and a wonderful cover which shows a ladder leaning against nothing at all, quite apt when you consider the subject matter of the document &amp;#8211; Indian microfinance. While we won&amp;#8217;t go into the microfinance bit at all in this post, please allow me a moment while we talk about the title.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Inverting the Pyramid&amp;#8221; is of course a reference to CK Prahlad&amp;#8217;s brilliant insight that human society is arranged like a pyramid, if you will, with a lot of poor people and only a few rich ones. Inverting the pyramid would entail changing this situation so that there are lots of rich people and only one or two poor ones. Apart from the charming naivete involved in this image, there also seems to be the unspoken conceit that microfinance is the tool to invert the pyramid. There&amp;#8217;s just one problem with this approach. Microfinance is very complicated. You need some capital (or a lot), friends at the banks, a relentless hunger for profit, tight opertions involving branches, centers, and meetings, cash to handle, new products to think up and offer, &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;MIS&lt;/span&gt; systems and biometric devices to evaluate, audits to conduct, human resources to manage and so on and so forth. I have a simpler solution for inverting the pyramid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;stand on your head&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it may or may not help to do this physically, mentally upending your notions for a little while will make the pyramid seem inverted, somewhat like staring at a stereogram long enough reveals the third dimension. Still finding it hard? Let me explain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you look at the world without the prejudices that have been instilled in you by your education or your upbringing, you will find that actually the world is an inverted pyramid. At the bottom, there are a very few dirty bastards, lazy fucks with no skills, questionable morals and absolutely no capacity for hard work. A supremely pampered lot, they can neither withstand variations in temperature nor can they go any length of time without a meal. Their capacity for pain is negligible and they require vast interventions of chemical substances, hospitals and indentured servants called doctors to maintain their health. Sometimes they lift weights, but mostly the weight they move around is their belly. Physically, they are mostly repulsive. Their major preoccupations are pieces of paper called money, the logo and brand of their personal belongings and whether they have more of these two things than anyone else. Their entire sense of worth comes from these things. they often do not care even about their close relatives. They communicate over great distances, often through blinking earpieces or other plasticky devices, but they rarely have anything but &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com&quot;&gt;banalities to share&lt;/a&gt;. If they give someone Re. 1, no matter how clearly that person is suffering and no matter how little that Re. 1 matters to them, they will not give any other person Re. 1 unless the sun has risen again, whereas they are perfectly capable of splurging thousands on a meal which they will then fill their toiletbowls with throughout the rest of the day. Their sense of place and time is so confused that sometimes they don&amp;#8217;t know which country they live in. Sometimes, they cannot even tell a human being apart from an animal. They treat the sacred earth as though it were toilet paper, to be used and thrown. Generosity is a meaningless word to them. This is really a pitiable sort. Thankfully, there are not so many of these specimens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the top of the pyramid we find a completely different kind of human. This is a human who is hardy, who has the capacity for labour, who has real skills. He can build a house, grow food, make things. He has no need for so many of the things that his bottom dwelling compatriot finds necessary &amp;#8211; air conditioners, cars, shoes, shampoos. He lives his whole life without them. He understands where his food, water and other necessities come from and he uses them carefully, husbanding the earth and the water. He consumes little. He is forced to work very hard, but he spends his leisure time playing with his family or praising the sacred. The meaning in his life comes from his family and his God. He has an immense capacity for suffering. He bears his pain with a heartbreaking dignity. He watches armies and emperors come and go. He has no need for industrial institutions. He gives up the produce of his work, mostly without complaint. He awaits his salvation in another life. If a bottom dweller enters his humble abode, he is treated with respect, given a meal or a cup of tea, far more than he himself might expect to receive in the bottom dwellers lavish abode. This man is to be respected. His suffering is to be admired and his way of being is to be aspired to. We are fortunate that the vast majority on earth are like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no need to invert the pyramid.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2010 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2010-06-09T12:00:00+05:30</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Technology - What's it good for.haml</title>
      <link>http://localhost:9393/blog/Technology+-+What%27s+it+good+for.haml</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;31 May 2010&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;UPDATE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2010/05/30/weekinreview/30rosenthal.html&quot;&gt;Our Fix-It Faith and the Oil Spill&lt;/a&gt; from the NY Times&lt;br /&gt;
and of course &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2010/may/30/oil-spills-nigeria-niger-delta-shell&quot;&gt;Nigeria&amp;#8217;s agony dwarfs the Gulf oil spill. The US and Europe ignore it&lt;/a&gt; (Guardian)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15 May 2010&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://t0.gstatic.com/images?q=tbn:4Wfw-ysz6L3TEM:http://2.4gigahertz.com/features/futk6900-ic-chip-2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display: none;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Frankly, I never thought that I would be asking this question. Having been an ardent advocate of technological progress, logical thinking and rationality in all spheres of life, this thought caught me by surprise, coming as it were not from some book (or web page) but completely unbidden one afternoon as I held my three week old son in my hands. The old questions arose again &amp;#8211; what, exactly, has the human race gained from technology and what has it lost? It becomes increasingly clear that what technology has allowed humans to do is to control their environment to such a degree that instead of having to collapse separately, the human race can now collapse all together as it runs up against hard limits that are in no way negotiable including peak oil, peak soil and peak water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does 21st century man really live better than at any other time? He lives longer but is his life any better? Fed on a steady diet of high fructose corn syrup he is prone to obesity and immunological disorders, diabetes and a host of other issues. Raised on a steady diet of TV infomercials and late night sales shows his view of the world is completely bounded by the transaction based economy, his sense of community rapidly dwindling to nothing. This brain of his craves shiny things like iPods and what not which hold him in a thrall which is beyond imbecility &amp;#8211; some smoothly animated &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SVG&lt;/span&gt; icons lead these people to egg on the mining operations far away, in someone&amp;#8217;s home. His social, economic and political structures do not include him except to suck out his life force through taxation and the periodic charade of voting. Theoretically he is free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These shiny objects have also allowed the geeks to speak with a sense of moral superiority &amp;#8211; we&amp;#8217;re building a new world you can hear them say. A connected world, one where information os free. And alas, that old problem &amp;#8211; what of humankind&amp;#8217;s moral compass? Who is tending that? Your logic has destroyed our myths but it is not obvious that man can live by information alone. Without the binding force of mythology man is alone &amp;#8211; a lone actor with no higher purpose, capable of nothing, susceptible to all the latest fads and impulses. He is today volatile and footloose. The technology that has enabled the construction of those giant steel teeth that bite the earth, those giant probes that thrust into her seeking, those whirring, buzzing, screaming gears that strip her naked is the same technology that has brought us to the ecological event horizon &amp;#8211; cleared forests, islands of plastic, huge open pit mines leaking their cyanide tailings into the wild &amp;#8211; disaster after disaster after disaster. Those that live quietly in the forest now have to move and be part of the great global dream of unlimited and instant consumption for all unless of course you are at the bottom of the pack in which case its one step forward and two steps back. Palliatives are offered for sure, but note that the fault is never one of the system. Vast injustices are the order of the day and yet it is never the system that is broken. More technology will fix it. That and overcoming one&amp;#8217;s personal failings, laziness and stupidity &amp;#8211; after all, Dhirubhai did it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the absence of the spiritual revolution, all will be lost. We don&amp;#8217;t need more technology. We don&amp;#8217;t need more monoculture fields and depleted topsoil. We don&amp;#8217;t need more consumption and haphazard disposal of metals and plastics to sustain you in your perpetual boredom, in your complete disconnect from society. We don&amp;#8217;t need more fighter drones, capable of taking out &amp;#8220;enemies&amp;#8221; in the night from afar. We don&amp;#8217;t need more electricity so that even more people can consume this ludicrous farce that is television. We have enough technology and yet the vast majority of the people on this planet do not even have anything resembling a life. Thousands of years of technological evolution but our capacity for expressing our compassion and for building a beautiful planet has not increased one jot. You say we have better drugs but only for the rich and mostly to cure their industrial diseases. Infant mortality is down but we are now 9 billion and staring species collapse in the face. Messages travel around the world in seconds, but there is no one to talk to and nothing to say. 140 characters is all we need these days. It&amp;#8217;s all we can deal with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also see: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.primitivism.com/primitivist-critique.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.primitivism.com/primitivist-critique.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2010 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2010-05-31T12:00:00+05:30</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Land.haml</title>
      <link>http://localhost:9393/blog/The+Land.haml</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;23 May 2010&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://mdb8.ibibo.com/04653616c7465645f5f757ed1da1519346055fb8957f82f5f66b2aa158a92d2b8ba1573a93634d7401e67d141040bed46754fa502.jpeg/fields-nature-landscape-bangalore-talakad.jpeg&quot; style=&quot;float:left;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The market (however attractive it may appear) is built on promises: the only source of wealth is the earth. Anyone who has land has access to energy, water, nourishment, shelter, healing, wisdom, ancestors and a grave. Ivan Illich spoke of &amp;#8220;a society of convivial tools that allows men to achieve purposes with energy fully under their control&amp;#8221;. The ultimate convivial tool, the mother of all the others, is the earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet the earth is more than a tool cupboard, for although the earth gives, it dictates its terms; and its terms alter from place to place. So it is that agriculture begets human culture; and cultural diversity, like biological diversity, flowers in obedience to the conditions that the earth imposes. The first and inevitable effect of the global market is to uproot and destroy land-based human cultures. The final and inevitable achievement of a rootless global market will be to destroy itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tlio.org.uk/TheLand/manifesto.html&quot;&gt;http://www.tlio.org.uk/TheLand/manifesto.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2010 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2010-05-23T12:00:00+05:30</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>L'Euro - c'est mort.haml</title>
      <link>http://localhost:9393/blog/L%27Euro+-+c%27est+mort.haml</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;May 13 2010&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/eur.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh lala&amp;#8230;.le bailout ne marche pas&amp;#8230;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2010 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2010-05-13T12:00:00+05:30</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Complexity, Entropy, Microfinance.haml</title>
      <link>http://localhost:9393/blog/Complexity%2C+Entropy%2C+Microfinance.haml</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;8 May 2010&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.williamgclark.com/entropy.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Many of us like to think of history as a deterministic process &amp;#8211; certain great individuals and institutions shaped the future of their civilization or the Earth or the story of man. It gives the human race a certain sense of control about its destiny and it just seems to make sense because after all history is histoire is historia is a story and a story has protagonists, actors, agents, drama. While there certainly have been many great men on this planet, it is not certain whether they were the shapers of history, the products of history or just the hapless puppet on the string of History, playing his or her part. What is certain though is that this mode of story-telling leaves out always one critical player in the whole scheme of human affairs &amp;#8211; the lovable rogue, the double edged sword, the mixed blessing, that pandora&amp;#8217;s box &amp;#8211; energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the dark times, when humans were still hunter gatherers, human society was very simple. Little better than the animals around us, we lived in tribal groups, ate what we could get our hands on or kill and generally led very simple lives. The average human would know a certain number of facts related to his daily survival and would spend any free time he had getting high around the campfire, or roughhousing with the children. Of course times were brutal, but they were about to get much more so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The discovery of agriculture led for the first time to a surplus of energy. People spend much time arguing about whether it is morally defensible for some to appropriate the produce of others. Others bemoan that fall from grace, that bad decision that condemned mankind to internecine warfare &amp;#8211; private property. What is often forgotten is that there might have been no choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The consumption of energy expresses itself in one way &amp;#8211; the doing of work &amp;#8211; and the doing of work expresses itself in terms of entropy &amp;#8211; the reduction of disorder where the work is done and a corresponding increase in the complexity of a system. Houses came to be built, which now needed maintainence. Farms and farmyard animals needed tending. Accounts need to be kept. An accountant class needed to be housed and clothed. Their idle offspring dreamed up new schemes to consume the excess energy. Boats were built&amp;#8230;.etc etc. The enrgy flows within local ecosystems were overridden and their feedback loops and self correcting mechanisms were pushed up into a higher level of complexity. Please see &lt;a href=&quot;http://theautomaticearth.blogspot.com/2010/01/january-1-2010-fractal-adaptive-cycles.html&quot;&gt;this wonderful writeup&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;http://theautomaticearth.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;The Automatic Earth&lt;/a&gt; for an explanation of the theory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the ways that this complexity expressed itself was through the creation of private property. While it is by no means a law of nature that complexity requires private ownership (see Linux), it seems to have been the path of least resistance, information being most accessible inside one head or one tightly knit entity. From this point onwards, the excess energy expressed itself in a decrease in the entropy of not just the physical world but also human society. From the disordered tribal mass human society came to be some very few elites at the top and a large mass of workers below. This seems to be the inevitable form of affairs given inputs of energy as no society evolved into an egalitarian society without the massive intervention of ideas and humanistic propaganda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This arrangement of society feeds upon itself and expresses itself in colonialism, slavery and latterly the appropriation of oil resources from wherver they may be found. It is this cycle of energy, work, complexity and more energy that has governed the trajectory of human life since the birth of agriculture. The problem with socialism, communism, anarchy, etc. is not that they go against human nature &amp;#8211; after all, greed and vileness do not encompass human nature as anyone who has met a human might know &amp;#8211; but that they go against this inexorable process of increasing complexity with its attendant reduction of entropy in human political affairs, leading to an elite and a proletarian class, no matter which way you slice it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, these situations are untenable, being dependent as they are on continuously increasing inputs of energy. Dmitry Orlov&amp;#8217;s awesome book &amp;#8220;Reinventing Collapse&amp;#8221; pins the peaking of Russian oil production as one of the causes for the collapse of the Soviet Union (and the global peak for the impending collapse of the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;USA&lt;/span&gt;). These situations are also untenable because they push feedback loops farther and farther out, overriding the natural tendencies of adaptive systems with their energy inputs and delaying collapse until it becomes a catastrophic event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vectors through which energy organises society usually have one defining characteristic &amp;#8211; they are conduits of information. Thus apart from the physical force of the king and his armies, the other two forms of political power came from information &amp;#8211; religious information for the priestly class and market information for the merchant class. With the decline of the grip of the priestly class on useful information, religion has become less and less important in world affairs. The influence of the merchant class, on the other hand, has gone from strength to strength.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vector that the merchant class has used to transfer information and organise society is &amp;#8220;money&amp;#8221;. Those bemoaning the loss of the gold standard do not understand that each of these vectors will try as hard as possible to gain as much share of the &amp;#8220;information capacity&amp;#8221; of society as possible. Thus money had to break free from the simplicity and rigidity of physical gold into more and more prevalent forms such as microchips and databases, and also into more and more complex forms such as CDOs et al.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every increase in complexity is an increase in energy consumption and vice versa. This is the reason why &amp;#8220;economic growth&amp;#8221; has attained such importance. The complexity treadmill we are on is one that picks up speed exponentially. It is not possible to slow it down or to turn it off or even to have it run at the same pace. The feedback loops have been pushed so far out that it now takes increasing amounts of energy usage to keep collapse at bay. Therefore, any attempt at &amp;#8220;green technology&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;sustainable business&amp;#8221; or other such eyewashes are doomed to fail, the only question being how awesome will the spectacle be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those who believe that microfinance is a great innovation of capitalism invariably turn out to be rich people, capitalists and those with a narrow world view of profitability as the ultimate good to be preserved at all costs. This imbecilic view is one that does horrifying violence to the natural world as well as to the aesthtic sense in human beings. What microfinance is, is the creeping of the organising vector of money into more and more remote regions. As the &amp;#8220;developed world&amp;#8221; is saturated with financial and transaction based ideas, this vector is seeking out greener pastures, so to speak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those who say that microfinance companies should provide healthcare and education are missing the point and will continue to be surprised when microfinance companies continue to insist that their mandate is only to deal in the ultimately meaningless task of shifting some symbols from one nominal place to another, from one account to another and to use up their life force, burn energy and go to extreme lengths to put people into debt where none existed before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does microfinance pull people out of poverty? While the jury seems to be out on this one, let us try and see what the chances are. In a viallage economy, there are some people performing some tasks, all of whom have been given the status of &amp;#8220;low value addition&amp;#8221; by society at large. Even though they tend to the soil and water tables, and produce the food that is necessary for life, these economic activities somehow add less value than say the moving of symbols from one place to another, or the photographing of naked women. The toil, labour and sacrifice of the pople who feed and clothe the country is somehow of less value than Lalit Modi&amp;#8217;s partying and Vijay Mallaya&amp;#8217;s debauhery. Regardless, in this low value addition economy let us introduce some debt in a quantum that is only enough to serve some individual need. Because of the low investment, there is really no substantive change in the nature of the activities performed. Perhaps a sewing machine or a cow will be bought and used. This is certainly a benefit. But does anyone count the cost that now perhaps 30% of everyone&amp;#8217;s effort is being siphoned out of the local economy and is enriching some &amp;#8220;social entrepreneur&amp;#8221; or some banker somewhere? Indeed, in exchange for something as banal, as commonplace and as yes, vulgar, as a sewing machine or cow the village now loses 30% of its produce to the city. This is the vector of money and this is how it shapes society. Are we expecting this force to produce equality and prosperity? Expecting a villager to produce an &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;ROI&lt;/span&gt; greater than Deutsche Bank &amp;#8211; is that asking too much? Is our society so sick that we cannot even provide these simple tools to the rural populace to make their lives more human?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is happening here is that the symbols of exchange are being loaned to people in echange for a staggering amount of rent. A huge amount of energy and effort is being expended so that some people will have something called a Rupee or a Taka or whatever, with which they can exchange their effort for the effort of others. The majority of this effort will be exchanged within the local economy, however, for the privilege of using these symbols a rent will be extracted. The burden of the rent, seen in the light of the limited utility of these symbols leads one to conclude that the monopoly on producing these symbols which lies with the state is nothing but a form of exploitation and opression. Those whose business it is to disseminate and collect these symbols, and worse, to employ the methods of coercion to recover these symbols are complicit in this oppression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now ask yourself, is microfinance a noble profession? Is it going to work? Or is it just another scheme to suck the life force of people and turn it into Ford Endeavours for the privileged?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are there any solutions? Ah, but one. Anarchy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2010 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2010-05-08T12:00:00+05:30</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Orlov Again.haml</title>
      <link>http://localhost:9393/blog/Orlov+Again.haml</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;20 Apr 2010&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.marriedtothesea.com/022310/i-hate-thinking.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perfectly formal systems of thought, such as logic and mathematics, seem the most rigorous, and have served as the guiding light for all other forms of thinking. But there&amp;#8217;s a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is that formal systems don&amp;#8217;t work. They have internal consistency, to be sure, and they can do all sorts of amusing tricks, but they don&amp;#8217;t map onto reality in a way that isn&amp;#8217;t essentially an act of violence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rest is &lt;a href=&quot;http://cluborlov.blogspot.com/2010/04/great-unreasoning.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2010 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2010-04-20T12:00:00+05:30</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tickets.haml</title>
      <link>http://localhost:9393/blog/Tickets.haml</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;07 Apr 2010 1730&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://horrorshowtunez.files.wordpress.com/2009/03/wonka_gold_ticket.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; A combination of Dimitry Orlov, Voltaire and Rage Against the Machine brought me to the idea that tickets should be the next currency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A ticket essentially represents a claim on anything, just like money. In current parlance tickets refer to claims mainly on peformances and public transportation but there is no reason why the ticket could not buy meals, conumer durables, public services or telecommunications access. A ticket is sold by a promoter and bought by a consumer. There exists also a particular thing or experience, the delivery of which is the basis of the transaction. Tickets can be issued by anyone for anything (within the framework of the law&amp;#8230;or perhaps even not).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such a system would have several cool things about it. To wit,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;It would be real money in the sense that every bit of currency in circulation would be backed by an actual physical thing. While being a real currency, it would still not suffer from the shortcomings of other &amp;#8220;real&amp;#8221; currencies such as gold by being extremely elastic in supply. It&amp;#8217;s value would not depend on the scarcity of the currency but rather on the scarcity (or abundance) of the ticketed item. i.e. brown rice prices will have to do more with the economic realities of the buyers region and not on global interest rate policy.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;It would remove the monopoly of Central Banks on printing money since the exchange of tickets will be perfectly legal. Anyone can print &amp;#8220;money&amp;#8221;, so to speak. The market would provide a basis for judging the value of those tickets. Central Banks, in the end, are the ultimate market imperfection. It is a testament to the efficacy of capitalist propaganda the this institution which completely corrupts the &amp;#8220;free market system&amp;#8221; has been accepted as a critical component of the same. The monopoly to print money, when coupled with the coercive power to collect taxes, represents less a facilitation of trade and commerce than a form of oppression.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Tickets are quasi local currencies. While there is no reason why someone from a distant place cannot buy tickets for performances in another place, chances are that most tickets would be exchanged locally and thus keep local economies thriving. A ticket can always be converted into cash for long distance transfer. It&amp;#8217;s convertibility into cash allows the ticket system to grow alongside the monetary system and thus represents creeping subversion instead of outright and traumatic overthrow.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;For the above reason, it would allow for the emergence of a &amp;#8220;real economics&amp;#8221;. Economics can return to the original meaning &amp;#8211; housekeeping, the arrangement of productive capacity to achieve the aims of society &amp;#8212; rather than some arcane, quasi-religion about multipliers and Laffer curves.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Tickets allow for better flow of information between buyers and sellers. People can demand things by signalling their willingness to pay for a ticket, advance bookings if you will. People in a position to provide will do so given adequate demand or adequate compensation either in cash or in other tickets. Some providers will eventually specialise in the exchange of tickets and thus become local points of reference for ticket value. Eventually, through the use of these clearing houses, information about the relative value of various tickets will disseminate through the economy and will make transacting in tickets as convenient as money.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ticket system basically means that it is the creation of items rather than the creation of debt which allows for the human species to exchange productive cappabilities.The problem of introducing a new kind of money is always of finding the correct starting point &amp;#8211; who has how much of what to start with? Since the ticket is not a giver of value but simply a tag on an item, this problem is dealt with. The money is just a name. And since everything has a name, there will always be exactly the same amount of money in the world as things with names.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, consider this extract from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.business.in.com/article/real-issue/the-indian-microfinance-impasse/11932/1&quot;&gt;http://www.business.in.com/article/real-issue/the-indian-microfinance-impasse/11932/1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most who say they started small businesses, including pushcarts selling firewood or vegetables or opened repair shops, say they suffered losses because people had no means to buy. With no way to earn, the lure of the increasingly available MFIs loans became hard to resist but harder to return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine that, in order to buy the produce of her neighbour, a Kolar woman has to go into debt. Instead of  being able to trade her productive capacity in a free manner, seh is obliged to obtain some currency through debt and then pay interest for the privilege of doing so. If you spend enough time looking at it, it begins to seem quite absurd. The Central Banks have done well to make themselves a part of the furniture, but it cannot be ignored &amp;#8211; central, monolithic, fiat currency systems create huge hurdles in the exonomic transactions of people with little or no access to such currency. The transaction and interest costs involved in exchanging their productive capacities for this currency are often directly responsible for their poverty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This money will be much freer than central bank provided money. Infact the whole central banking system begins to look absurd in front of what one might call a Proletarian Monetary System.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2010 17:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2010-04-07T17:30:00+05:30</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kollapsnik 2.haml</title>
      <link>http://localhost:9393/blog/Kollapsnik+2.haml</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;7 Apr 2010&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_-b-kpMH_7eM/Sjeu5vQWuGI/AAAAAAAABFU/if_YC8i8AXE/s400/slide13.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lack of [a] money [system] makes certain things very difficult. Examples include gambling, loan sharking, extortion, bribery and fraud. It also makes it more difficult to hoard wealth, or to extract it out of a community and ship it somewhere else in a conveniently compact form. When we use money, we cede power to those who create money (by creating debt) and who destroy money (by cancelling debt). We also empower the ranks of people whose area of expertise is in the manipulation of arbitrary rules and arithmetic abstractions rather than in engaging directly with the physical world. This veil of metaphor allows them to mask appalling levels of violence, representing it symbolically as a mere paper-shuffling exercise. People, animals, entire ecosystems become mere numbers on a piece of paper. On the other hand, this ability to represent dissimilar objects using identical symbols causes a great deal of confusion. For instance, I have heard rather intelligent people declare that government funds, which have been allocated to making failed financial institutions look solvent, could be so much better spent feeding widows and orphans. There is no understanding that astronomical quantities of digits willed into existence and transferred between two computers (one at a central bank, another at a private bank) cannot be used to directly nourish anyone, because food cannot be willed into existence by a central banker or anyone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply amazing. I have ordered his book &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flipkart.com/book/reinventing-collapse-dmitry-orlov-soviet/0865716064&quot;&gt;Reinventing Collapse&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;http://flipkart.com&quot;&gt;flipkart.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2010 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2010-04-07T12:00:00+05:30</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kollapsnik.haml</title>
      <link>http://localhost:9393/blog/Kollapsnik.haml</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;6 Apr 2010&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_-b-kpMH_7eM/S5IJjQZboVI/AAAAAAAABO0/wCEzP0eYzHs/s320/VladimirKato_Sadburger.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; Dimitry Orlov is a doomer&amp;#8217;s doomer and he writes a superb doomer blog at &lt;a href=&quot;http://cluborlov.com&quot;&gt;cluborlov.com&lt;/a&gt;. Most intelligent people will concede that the current paradigms of human society are clearly unsustainable. Exponential growth in limited systems is a mathematical impossibility and the only debate is about whether a new myth and a new paradigm will arise before or after catastrophic system collapse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I leave you with a very touching guest post at cluborlov.com. Here&amp;#8217;s a small excerpt&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I feel the pernicious influence of all this on my own family right here and now. You don&amp;#8217;t have to be a brilliant visionary to realize that in the current situation all these endless suburbs, built on the North American model, are slowly but surely turning into mass graves for the millions of former members of the middle class. Those that do not turn into mass graves will become nature preserves &amp;#8211; stocked with wild animals that were once human. My family is turning feral under my very eyes. Lack of resources has forced us to live according to the Soviet model &amp;#8211; three generations under one roof. There are six of us, of which only one works, who is, consequently, exasperated and embittered. The rest of the household is gradually going insane from idleness and boredom. The television is never turned off. The female side of the family has been sucked into social networks and associated toys. Everyone is cultivating their own special psychosis, and periodically turns vicious. In these suburbs, a person without a car is as if without legs, and joblessness does not allow any of us to earn money for gas, and so the house is almost completely isolated from the outside world. The only information that seeps in comes from the lying mass media. And I understand that millions of families throughout America live this way! This is how people turn into &amp;#8220;teabaggers,&amp;#8221; while their children join street gangs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read the whole thing &lt;a href=&quot;http://cluborlov.blogspot.com/2010/03/corn-madness.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2010 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2010-04-06T12:00:00+05:30</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mumbai Has Turned Its Back On Itself.haml</title>
      <link>http://localhost:9393/blog/Mumbai+Has+Turned+Its+Back+On+Itself.haml</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;3 Apr 2010&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Update&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/bollywood/news-interviews/200-crores-down-the-drain/articleshow/5754180.cms&quot;&gt;200 crores down the drain&lt;/a&gt; Apparently all of 2010 has been flops as well. Bollywood is in deep trouble. The inbred coteries of erstwhile star-nephews and nieces, aided by those know-it-all MBAs in the production houses are driving the industry to rock bottom. Stay tuned for updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;19 Nov 2009&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/neha.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A venerable institution of Mumbai is moribund. Bollywood lies gasping in a shallow puddle of its own ineptitude. When my wife &amp;#8211; a dedicated follower of Bollywood &amp;#8211; suddenly started skipping films, I realised something was horribly wrong. It all started, in my estimation, with the producer&amp;#8217;s strike. Whatever the reasons, the strike has contributed significantly to this state of affairs. It made people realise that they could live without movies, and perhaps that their life might even be better for it. The extra Rs. 1000 a week was probably being deployed elsewhere at better bang for buck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bollywood chose to end the strike with a choice that destroyed it. The first film after the strike was &amp;#8220;Kal Kisne Dekha&amp;#8221; starring newcomer Jackie Bhagnani , a most cynical choice of film. The film community could at this point have shown that it really cared about it&amp;#8217;s audience and released a big starrer to draw the crowds back. Instead, the MBAs walking the corridors of power in Bollywood today counted up the beans and decided that no, we lead with a flop &amp;#8211; that way New York will seem better than it actually is. This choice was fatal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some pictures I took at &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;PVR&lt;/span&gt; a few weeks ago, and one of Fun Republic today. These are of course isolated incidents and I present them as indications rather than proof of a crisis. Judge for yourself from your own experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/fun+republic.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left;width: 45%;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/pvr+phoenix+mills+1.JPG&quot; style=&quot;float:left;width: 45%;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/pvr+phoenix+mills+2.JPG&quot; style=&quot;float:left;width: 45%;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/pvr+phenix+mills+3.JPG&quot; style=&quot;float:left;width: 45%;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the VPs of New Product development continue to fawn over the stars and engage in ritual self love. Reading their tweets is quite instructive. One such young man saw fit to wish Lara Dutta a happy puppy day. Meanwhile, box office registers resound with the deafening sounds of silence. The only people at Fun Republic yesterday were there to see Alphaville, a sublime film by the master Godard and a sentimental offering from Chabrol called Le Beau Serge which was nonetheless far more satisfying than the recent tepid produce from Bollywoodland. To be noted also is that these screenings, located as they were in the heart of film producer land (Lokhandwala), still managed to attract precisely zero people from the production companies. Apparently, there is nothing that these people need to learn from Godard and Chabrol or any of the other new wave directors on at the French New Wave Film Festival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what happens when you deny the proles a decent education. You end up with a nation that has no way to entertain itself, let alone achieve anything else. Reading Rajni Bakhi&amp;#8217;s new book &amp;#8220;Bazaar, Conversations and Freedom&amp;#8221; (a more detailed review once I finish it), I learnt an interesting fact. The author of England&amp;#8217;s blueprint for the welfare state said that it was imperative to provide the minimum to everyone because without it, the nation would fall prey to, among other things, idleness. This is interesting because the conventional view is that giving things to people for free breeds idleness, atleast according to the capitalists. However, a cursory glance at what drivers do during their massive waitings everyday easily confirms Lord Beveredge&amp;#8217;s thesis &amp;#8211; a person without education can do nought but be idle. Only education enables him to become productive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The state film development corporations (&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;NFDC&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;CFSI&lt;/span&gt; and Films Division) are also not performing. Where is their output? How hard is it choose maybe 50 directors a year and give them a couple of crore to experiment freely? After all, film making is not just socially useful but it is economically important too. film theaters draw audiences which support the local economy of restaurants and shops. Without film makers, these economies collapse. The desolation at Fun Republic was mirrored in the restaurants of Lokhandwala&amp;#8217;s main strip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laxmikant&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;The Man Beyond the Bridge&amp;#8221;, which won an award at Toronto, is never going to get a release. The distribution system will ensure that Bela Negi&amp;#8217;s refreshing film Dayen Ya Bayen is probably going straight to TV as well. These are just two instances that I know of. There are also many, many talented indivduals who will never get a break because those who have to judge their projects simply do not have the analytical tools to do so. Replacing the &amp;#8220;lala&amp;#8221; producer with a business professional has been a big mistake. Atleast the lala is susceptible to whimsy and there is a chance that he will take a risk on something. Organisations, on the other hand, are coldly rational, risk averse and worst of all, love profit more than cinema. They are paying the price now, but there is no guarantee that they will learn the right lessons. Numerology, astrology, recession and a host of other reasons will be pulled out to justify the state of affairs, but no one will be able to see that the fault lies in the films, and the people making those films. After all, as Godard points out in Alphaville, organisations have an imperative to not just survive but also to grow as big and strong as possible. The state of affairs is not going to improve, even with the collapse of several producers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the light of Mumbai&amp;#8217;s soul grows dim. Business has ruined another beautiful thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Updates:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/Will-year-end-releases-end-Bollywood-slump/articleshow/5308872.cms&quot;&gt;Will Year End Releases end Bollywood slump?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/Hollywood-thrills-make-up-for-Bollywoods-flop-show/articleshow/5357570.cms&quot;&gt;Hollywood thrills make up for Bollywoods flop show&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2010 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2010-04-03T12:00:00+05:30</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interview in Microfinance Insights.haml</title>
      <link>http://localhost:9393/blog/Interview+in+Microfinance+Insights.haml</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;31 Mar 2010&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://mostfit.in/images/mostfit_logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mostfit.in&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;MOSTFIT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and myself were briefly featured in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microfinanceinsights.com/comments_tab.asp?id=138&quot;&gt;Microfinance Insights.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2010 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2010-03-31T12:00:00+05:30</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elegance, Minimalism, etc.haml</title>
      <link>http://localhost:9393/blog/Elegance%2C+Minimalism%2C+etc.haml</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;29 Mar 2010 1645&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/site-images/mondrian.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left; width: 350px;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;Of late, I&amp;#8217;ve been wondering if minimalism, atleast the way it is practiced on the web, is worth it and whether it is a viable philosophy. If you look at any of the minimalist web design listings, you&amp;#8217;ll basically see a plethora of sites in black and white. Why? Is minimalism condemned to be ugly and boring? Or is there something the matter with ones interpretation of the word?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, minimalism is essentially a formal concept, not a functional one. It&amp;#8217;s more about the form of an action than the results of the action. Happiness does not lie in reducing activity, it lies in mindful and fulfilling activity. Thus minimalism of the sort which limits ones ability to do anything &amp;#8212; in web design terms, to be usable and unique &amp;#8212; is not appealing to me. I cannot eschew the use of color just to fulfill some minimalist fantasy. Minimalism as a life philosophy is a self contradictory philosophy, and is a half-baked yearning for something else. The end point of minimalism per se is death &amp;#8211; no more need for anything. At each point along this route, there is a further point you can go to. Have you given up color in your websites? Good. Now give up your websites. I have no problem with people choosing the hermetic way, but it seems a little stupid to be stranded halfway down the path to nothing, constantly justifying everything against an ethic that is contradictory with itself and perhaps even opposed to life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My personal preference has changed from a quest for minimalism to a quest for elegance. The quest for elegance encompasses much of the quest for minimalism but is free from the pitfalls of the latter because elegance is a functional, not formal construct. Elegance is also free to break from the monasticity of minimalism and thus is not hemmed in by those internal contradictions. Taking things away does not always make them more elegant. Some mindfulness is required in these matters, and blindly eschewing jQuery or &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;AJAX&lt;/span&gt; is akin to making a hut withut a roof. Might work fine in some cases, but surely not everytime. And if you&amp;#8217;re building a hut, you might as well put in a roof because otherwise why build a hut at all?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, elegance leaves one with choices. Minimalism, not so much. My own frustrations with minimalism for its own sake began with a recent attempt to reinstall Arch Linux. I wanted a bare Linux that runs fast, has no flash or gloss and is rough and tough and rock steady. A quick download later, looking at the login screen for Arch Linux, I was overcome by a wave of ennui. Building an Arch Linux system is a daunting task, one that takes several days of concentrated effort and even then it might never work properly. Why? I asked myself, must I go through this? In a flash the answer came to me &amp;#8211; the minimalist way would be to not waste, and so not wasting my time would be minimalism. Though not quite, right? After all, minimalism isn&amp;#8217;t about saving time or being happy. Minimalism is about doing with less. Elegance on the other hand is doing more with less. Doing things well. Making it look easy. I tossed my Arch Linux install disk out of the window and was happy. Replacing unthinking minimalism with a mindful elegance as my guiding construct has solved many of my problems. I can now use Ubuntu and Gnome for their beauty and run XMonad inside Gnome for its elegance. I can blog on tumblr.com instead of writing my own blog engine in 40 lines or less of ruby (I can, but I don&amp;#8217;t. I actually prefer writing and publishing from emacs)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I can now redesign the blog, add some more colors to make the site more beautiful and also more user-friendly and I can do all this with a clean conscience. The goal of life is to be happy, not to do without. The whole reason to do without stuff is because it gets in the way of being happy. For some people, and for me, being happy involves free time and the sun on my arms, the outdoors, travel, flying and programming and my family. I don&amp;#8217;t really need anything else. Infact, most other things just get in the way. But not colors on my web page. Not jQuery. Not CSS3. Let&amp;#8217;s be realistic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2010 16:45:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2010-03-29T16:45:00+05:30</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Barthes.haml</title>
      <link>http://localhost:9393/blog/Barthes.haml</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;29 Mar 2010&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/7/7c/RolandBarthes.jpg/250px-RolandBarthes.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; I&amp;#8217;m currently immersed in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roland_Barthes&quot;&gt;Roland Barthes&lt;/a&gt; Reader, a collection of writings by the French philosopher and semiotician. I&amp;#8217;ve only read a few of the pieces and they are amazing. While I will not attempt to write a review of the pieces or add my comments to Barthes&amp;#8217; work, I do want to say that if you enjoy reading Umberto Eco&amp;#8217;s essays and non-fiction pieces, do try Barthes. He is dazzlingly bright and while complex, never hides behind undefined terms or obfuscated language. His insights into myths and bourgeois propaganda are eye-opening to the student of society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flipkart.com/roland-barthes-reader/0099224917-pnw3fw9zrf&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://img.fkcdn.com/img/914/9780099224914.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:right;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; You can buy the book from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flipkart.com/roland-barthes-reader/0099224917-pnw3fw9zrf&quot;&gt;flipkart.com&lt;/a&gt; This book will be well worth it because its the kind of book that one would probably want to spend a long time with.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2010 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2010-03-29T12:00:00+05:30</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Himalayan Odyssey.haml</title>
      <link>http://localhost:9393/blog/Himalayan+Odyssey.haml</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;28 Mar 2010&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some friends of mine are currently engaged in a phenomenal adventure of a lifetime &amp;#8211; flying paragliders from Billing in himachal Pradesh to Pelling in Sikkim, a distance of about 1600 kms. They&amp;#8217;re currently a little more than halfway, approaching Pokhara in Nepal. You can follow their adventures at &lt;a href=&quot;http://himalayanodyssey.org&quot;&gt;their website&lt;/a&gt; and you can check out a fresh set of pictures that will make you green with envy &lt;a href=&quot;http://picasaweb.google.com/himodc/HimalayanOdysseyExpedition201002?authkey=Gv1sRgCJH_r42A9PK_ggE&amp;amp;feat=flashalbum&quot;&gt;over here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s a small sample&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://lh6.ggpht.com/_lqYl33mXoz4/S60LTTK3F2I/AAAAAAAAAI4/SEPMMNZ2Q2k/s640/P1060632.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://lh5.ggpht.com/_lqYl33mXoz4/S60MgZcuniI/AAAAAAAAALU/Vsnw53R3M5g/s640/P1060782.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2010 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2010-03-28T12:00:00+05:30</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Choppers.haml</title>
      <link>http://localhost:9393/blog/Choppers.haml</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;15 Mar 2010&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://neatorama.cachefly.net/images/2007-07/heli-rickshaw.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
From the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;DNA&lt;/span&gt; Newspaper, we learn that there will be &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dnaindia.com/mumbai/report_choppers-will-zip-past-in-sky-soon_1355409&quot;&gt;dedicated corridors for choppers in Mumbai and Delhi&lt;/a&gt;. It &lt;strong&gt;is&lt;/strong&gt; nice to know that the government is doing something to ease the plight of those &amp;#8220;chopper-hopping corporate honchos and business tycoons in Mumbai&amp;#8221;. It is even more heartening to know that India is making progress, that now certain citizens can actually afford the Rs. 5000 ride from the suburbs to downtown. Politicians, industrialists and film stars need no longer sweat it out in traffic jams amongst the proles, with their chapped hands and sweaty nightcaps. Of course, with the market economy and capitalism full steam ahead, it is only a matter of time until all citizens can just take the chopper to the mall. Perhaps that is the reason that the roads have fallen into such disrepair. Why repair things that no one will need to use once we&amp;#8217;re all rich?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the spoilsports at &lt;a href=&quot;http://stophelipad.org&quot;&gt;stophelipad.org&lt;/a&gt;, these choppers are noisy. So noisy they say that it can knock stuff of shelves and shatter glass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://stophelipad.org/images/helicopter_sound_chart_small.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, it looks like the denizens of Dindoshi are just going to have to take this one up the arse then. Can&amp;#8217;t let a few poor people get in the way of progress can we? After all, if they worked a bit harder and weren&amp;#8217;t so stupid then they could ride the choppers too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2010 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2010-03-15T12:00:00+05:30</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poor Obama Supporters.obama.haml</title>
      <link>http://localhost:9393/blog/Poor+Obama+Supporters.obama.haml</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;17 Feb 2010&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/obama.png&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Obama fucks up&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A prescient blogger wrote &lt;a href=&quot;http://svs.webfactional.com/blog/?p=22&quot;&gt;this piece&lt;/a&gt; last November, which immediately drew flak from all across the globe. Now, a year after Obama&amp;#8217;s election and the humongous slide in his popularity to below 50%, we see yet again that old thesis &amp;#8211; power corrupts and absolute power corrupts absolutely &amp;#8211; being borne out. Proletarians who look to the heavens for deliverance will always be disappointed. The system will never wreck itself. The prescient blogger, seeing the world through a (gasp!) Marxist lens avoided being fooled while the rest of the world went into gushing adoration. That prescient blogger is, of course, me on a different blog. Here is another very smart man on Obama &amp;#8211; Matt Taibbi writes on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rollingstone.com/politics/story/31234647/obamas_big_sellout&quot;&gt;Obama&amp;#8217;s Big Sellout&lt;/a&gt; in Rolling Stone&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proles, everyday I marvel at the twists of logic that the human mind is capable off in arriving at its conclusions. Our naivete is unmatched in nature. Kick a cat once and it will avoid you for life, but you can piss on humans forever provided you tell them a nice story while doing it. Ooooh look, he&amp;#8217;s black. Conclusion? He is on our side. Wow!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyday you see around you evidence that the system of limitless accumulation of power is leaving you voiceless and yet you live your life as though you yourself will someday have limitless power. You dream of it as you hang from the straps, hurtling past the slums and &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;MHADA&lt;/span&gt; colonies by the tracks. You continue to choose between Congress, &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;BJP&lt;/span&gt;, Shiv Sena, &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;MNS&lt;/span&gt; or whatever other party you may care to name as though it makes a difference &amp;#8211; as though these are not all ultimately leading to the same choice &amp;#8211; rule by corruption. You worship money, when what you need is a clean city, a comfortable commute, a decent amount of leisure, good healthcare and education for your children. You live as though it is just a matter of time before you break through into the privileged club of millionaires. Meanwhile, the end of the line arrives and you have to get off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that the prole&amp;#8217;s disappointment with Barack is getting through to their conscious minds, it might be useful to talk about propaganda, the endless barrage of messages, liminal and subliminal, that you receive through the day. Just like the worship of Obama during his election, all these messages from the mainstream media have an agenda. Sometimes, like with advertising, the agenda is very overt. At other times, it is in better taste to keep the agenda hidden, but there is always an agenda. One of the messages you always receive is connected with a very simple word &amp;#8211; anarchy. Immediately your mind sees a rioting mob, a strapping young lad hurling a Molotov cocktail while looters carry away other people&amp;#8217;s private property. Am I right? The word anarchy has been made to mean so much like disorder and chaos that we cannot even consider the term anymore without asking &amp;#8211; but with no ruler, why would there be any order? This response is typicalof people who have been taught to always see their fellow man as a competitor, to see humans as greedy and violent beings and who will always prefer a despotic ruler to no ruler at all. Who will accept Barack Obama and his Wall Street handlers before they will trust the instincts of their neighbour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I leave you with a link to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anarchism_in_Spain&quot;&gt;Barcelona Anarchists&lt;/a&gt;, active in Spain before the civil war, and hopefully, a thought on how to live life without this parasitic political system and the rule of the few over the many.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2010 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2010-02-17T12:00:00+05:30</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To All Those Working In Television.html</title>
      <link>http://localhost:9393/blog/To+All+Those+Working+In+Television.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;15 Feb 2010&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/ball-licker-vadhu.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;!&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;DOCTYPE&lt;/span&gt; html &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;PUBLIC&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#8220;-//W3C//&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;DTD&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;XHTML&lt;/span&gt; 1.0 Strict//EN&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml1/&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;DTD&lt;/span&gt;/xhtml1-strict.dtd&amp;#8221;&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;html xmlns='http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml'&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;head&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;title&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      To all those who work in TV&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/title&gt;
&amp;lt;!&amp;#8212;
metadata
&amp;#8212;&amp;gt;
&lt;meta content='presentr' name='generator' /&gt;
&lt;meta content='1.0' name='version' /&gt;
&lt;meta content='20100120' name='presdate' /&gt;
&lt;meta content='Prole' name='author' /&gt;
&lt;meta content='Prole.in' name='company' /&gt;
&amp;lt;!&amp;#8212;
configuration parameters
&amp;#8212;&amp;gt;
&lt;meta content='slideshow' name='defaultView' /&gt;
&lt;meta content='hidden' name='controlVis' /&gt;
&amp;lt;!&amp;#8212;
style sheet links
&amp;#8212;&amp;gt;
&lt;link href='/stylesheets/tv.css' rel='stylesheet' type='text/css' /&gt;
&amp;lt;!&amp;#8212;
S5 JS
&amp;#8212;&amp;gt;
&lt;script language=&quot;javascript&quot; src=&quot;/javascripts/instant/instant.js&quot; type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;script language=&quot;javascript&quot; src=&quot;/javascripts/jquery-1.3.2.js&quot; type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;script language=&quot;javascript&quot; src=&quot;/javascripts/jTypeWriter.js&quot; type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;script language=&quot;javascript&quot; src=&quot;/javascripts/jquery.fxqueues-2.0.3.js&quot; type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;script language=&quot;javascript&quot; src=&quot;/javascripts/anim.js&quot; type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/head&gt;
&lt;body&gt;
&lt;div class='layout'&gt;
&lt;div id='controls'&gt;
&amp;lt;!&amp;#8212;
DO &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;NOT&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;EDIT&lt;/span&gt;
&amp;#8212;&amp;gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id='currentSlide'&gt;
&amp;lt;!&amp;#8212;
DO &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;NOT&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;EDIT&lt;/span&gt;
&amp;#8212;&amp;gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id='header'&gt;
To all those who work in TV&amp;#8230;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class='presentation'&gt;
&lt;img class='x' id='img_stop' src='/images/television-basura.jpg' style='position:absolute; top: 40px; left: 30px;' /&gt;
&lt;div style='position:absolute; top: 85px; left: 150px; color: white; width: 300px;'&gt;
&lt;div style='width:300px'&gt;
&lt;h1 class='x black' id='quit'&gt;
Please quit!
&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div class='x black' id='madness'&gt;
This is madness&amp;#8230;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;img class='instant x' id='blv' src='/images/ball-licker-vadhu.jpg' style='z-index: 1; position: absolute; left: 650px;' /&gt;
&lt;div class='x black' id='celebrate' style='position: absolute;width: 350px; left: 600px; top: 150px;z-index: 2;'&gt;
&lt;a href='#' onclick=&quot;javascript:$('#no').slideToggle()&quot;&gt;
are we celebrating child brides..?
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class='subtext' id='no' style='display: none;'&gt;
Is she cute?
Does your daughter identify with her?
Does this scare you?
Why not?
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;img class='instant x' id='padmini' src='/images/hot_hindu.jpg' style='z-index: 2; position: absolute; left: 950px;' /&gt;
&lt;div class='x black' id='glorify' style='position: absolute;width: 250px; left: 900px; top: 250px;z-index: 2;'&gt;
&lt;a href='#' onclick=&quot;javascript:$('#oohlala').slideToggle()&quot;&gt;
are we glorifying the ritual honor burning of women?
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class='subtext' id='oohlala' style='display: none;'&gt;
..although Tejaswini is easily hot enough to burn through any old pile of logs without help&amp;#8230;mmmmm
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;img class='instant x' id='india_tv' src='/images/india_tv.jpg' style='z-index: 2; position: absolute; left: 1150px;' /&gt;
&lt;div class='x black' id='news' style='position: absolute;width: 150px; left: 1280px; top: 150px;z-index: 2;'&gt;
&lt;a href='#' onclick=&quot;javascript:$('#yeah_right').slideToggle();false;&quot;&gt;
Is this news?
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class='subtext' id='yeah_right' style='display: none;'&gt;
&amp;#8230;there&amp;#8217;s a lady who knows&amp;#8230;
rest of the world is fucking stupid&amp;#8230;.we have the real stairway to heaven.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;img class='instant x' id='bhoot-aaa' src='/images/kapde%20ka%20bhootaaa.jpg' style='z-index: 2; position: absolute; left: 1190px; top: 180px' /&gt;
&lt;div class='x black' id='news2' style='position: absolute;width: 150px; left: 1280px; top: 310px;z-index: 2;'&gt;
&amp;#8230;or this?
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1 class='x black' style='position: absolute;width: 150px; left: 1480px; top: -40px;z-index: 2;opacity: 0.7;'&gt;
i could go on&amp;#8230;
&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 class='x black' style='position: absolute;width: 350px; left: 1680px; top: -40px;z-index: 2;opacity: 0.7;'&gt;
and what is it for?
&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;img class='instant x' id='money' src='/images/money.jpg' style='z-index: 2; position: absolute; left: 1690px; top: 137px' /&gt;
&lt;h1 class='black x' id='salary' style='position: absolute;width: 350px; left: 2100px; top: -0px;z-index: 2;opacity: 0.7;'&gt;
do you know where this money comes from?
who pays your salary?
&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;img class='x' id='bg2' src='/images/manifest_destiny.jpg' style='z-index: 0; position: absolute; left: 2500px; top: -40px; height: 600px;' /&gt;
&lt;img class='x instant' id='dr_evil' src='/images/Dr_Evil.jpg' style='z-index: 1; position: absolute; left: 2500px; top: -40px;' /&gt;
&lt;h1 class='black x' style='position: absolute; left: 2580px; top: 300px;z-index: 2;opacity: 0.7;'&gt;
..advertisers&amp;#8230;
&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;img class='x instant' id='spend' src='/images/spend.png' style='z-index: 1; position: absolute; left: 3000px; top: 0px;' /&gt;
&lt;h1 class='black x' style='position: absolute;width: 350px; left: 3100px; top: 240px;z-index: 2;opacity: 0.7;'&gt;
..which leads to&amp;#8230;
&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;img class='x instant' id='pollution' src='/images/pollution.jpg' style='z-index: 1; position: absolute; left: 3300px; top: 0px;' /&gt;
&lt;h1 class='black x' style='position: absolute;width: 350px; left: 3700px; top: -40px;z-index: 1;opacity: 0.7;'&gt;
..which leads to&amp;#8230;
&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;img class='x instant' id='fish_dying' src='/images/fish_dying_pollution.jpg' style='z-index: 1; position: absolute; left: 3900px; top: -40px;' /&gt;
&lt;img class='x instant' id='deforestation' src='/images/deforestation.jpg' style='z-index: 1; position: absolute; left: 4000px; top: 240px;' /&gt;
&lt;h1 class='black x' style='position: absolute;width: 350px; left: 4380px; top: -40px;z-index: 2;opacity: 0.7;'&gt;
and lets not forget who you really work for&amp;#8230;
&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;img class='x instant' id='murdoch' src='/images/murdoch.jpg' style='z-index: 2; position: absolute; left: 4400px; top: 140px;' /&gt;
&lt;div class='x black' id='planman' style='position: absolute;width: 270px; left: 4400px; top: 350px;z-index: 2;'&gt;
&lt;a href='#' onclick=&quot;javascript:$('#no').slideToggle()&quot;&gt;
the man with the plan&amp;#8230;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class='x black' id='plan' style='position: absolute;width: 250px; left: 4700px; top: 0px;z-index: 2;'&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;The Sun&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Star Plus&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;San Antonio Star&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;BSkyB&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;etc&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;etc&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;img class='x instant' id='sunflower' src='/images/educating.jpg' style='z-index: 1; position: absolute; left: 5300px; top: 0px;' /&gt;
&lt;div class='x black' id='educate' style='position: absolute;width: 450px; left: 5200px; top: 250px;z-index: 2;'&gt;
&lt;a href='#' onclick=&quot;javascript:$('#no').slideToggle()&quot;&gt;
you are educating the children of this country.
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class='subtext' id='no' style='display: none;'&gt;
Please think about what you are doing. Their future and our future is in your hands.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;img class='x' id='postit' src='/images/post-it.png' style='z-index: 1; position: absolute; left: 6800px; top: 40px;' /&gt;
&lt;h1 class='x black' id='thanks' style='position: absolute;width: 450px; left: 7900px; top: 250px;z-index: 2;'&gt;
thanks for listening
&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;div id=&amp;#8220;disqus_thread&amp;#8221; style = &amp;#8220;position: absolute; width: 800px; left:8500px; opacity: 1; padding: 10px; font-size: 16px;background: white; color: black; border-radius: 10px; font-family: Georgia;&amp;#8221;&amp;gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
	&amp;lt;div id=&amp;#8220;bookends&amp;#8221; style = &amp;#8220;position: absolute; left:9500px&amp;#8221;&amp;gt;lalala&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot; src=&quot;http://disqus.com/forums/prole/embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;noscript&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://disqus.com/forums/prole/?url=ref&quot;&gt;View the discussion thread.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://disqus.com&quot; class=&quot;dsq-brlink&quot;&gt;blog comments powered by &lt;span class=&quot;logo-disqus&quot;&gt;Disqus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt; 
	  //&amp;lt;![&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;CDATA&lt;/span&gt;[
	  &lt;p&gt;(function() {&lt;br /&gt;
	    var links = document.getElementsByTagName(&amp;#8216;a&amp;#8217;);&lt;br /&gt;
	    var query = &amp;#8216;?&amp;#8217;;&lt;br /&gt;
	    for(var i = 0; i &amp;lt; links.length; i++) {&lt;br /&gt;
	    if(links[i].href.indexOf(&amp;#8216;#disqus_thread&amp;#8217;) &amp;gt;= 0) {&lt;br /&gt;
          query += &amp;#8216;url&amp;#8217; + i + &amp;#8216;=&amp;#8217; + encodeURIComponent(links[i].href) + &amp;#8216;&amp;amp;&amp;#8217;;&lt;br /&gt;
	    }&lt;br /&gt;
	    }&lt;br /&gt;
	    document.write(&amp;#8216;&amp;#8217; + query + &amp;#8216;&amp;#8220;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/&amp;#8217; + &amp;#8216;script&amp;gt;&amp;#8217;);&lt;br /&gt;
	    })();&lt;br /&gt;
	    //]]&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id='footer'&gt;
&lt;p&gt;19 Jan 2010&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2010 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2010-02-15T12:00:00+05:30</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Antichrist.haml</title>
      <link>http://localhost:9393/blog/Antichrist.haml</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2 Feb 2010&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Lars von Trier should not make films&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.cjsf.ca/aereviews/images/antichrist.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left;width:350px;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually don&amp;#8217;t mean that in a bad way. It&amp;#8217;s just that the film medium is wasted on him. Dogville might have been a great critical success but some actors on a stage is not really a film. Yes, it is projected at 24 fps but the art is not that of making a film. A few dark locations, completely artificial places and claustrophobic situations are the mainstay of his newest, Antichrist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The situation is so terribly cliched that from the very start, art is impossible. A couple whose child has died from falling out the window while they were having sex. Perhaps the poor infant had been driven mad by the sheer mediocrity of the background score. How can you come back from that unless your intention was to make a melodrama? Extreme melodrama, gratuitous violence and sado-masochistic sex make up the rest of the film, coupled with dialogue that is so boring it had all to be shot in extreme close-up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, politically this film is a complete failure. If all you have to say is that there is violence in the world then you are not really doing anyone any favours. Everybody knows this. What the people need to know is that there is something called humanity. Shots of an eagle eating a dead chick are not edifying in any way. Another seminal scene is the one where a tumescent penis ejaculates blood. Another has a dead chick being crawled over by ants.  Infact, it is precisely this sort of shitty glorification of viollence that is at this point completely out of synch with the times. Our species knows well enough how to hate. What it needs is a new mythology based on love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.theimagist.com/files/images/7217.thumbnail.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:right;width: 33%;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;How different this film was from Stalker. While watching the interminable film on fast forward, I got to thinking about Stalker. Imagine my surprise when the end credits start with &amp;#8220;Dedicated to Andrey Tarkovsky&amp;#8221;. Wow&amp;#8230;is that all you learned from him&amp;#8230;? How to light some scenes? Stalker is poetry because you can see that the director is so confident on his canvas that he can make each frame speak. He can imbue anything with a quality of his choice as he paints emotions on the screen. Antichrist has no canvas. Anonymous places, tight framing and dialogues full of sobbing are all that pass for emotion in this film. That is what I have been saying all along &amp;#8211; this is not a film. It has no weltanschuung. It has no zeitgeist.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2010 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2010-02-02T12:00:00+05:30</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dr Strangelove.haml</title>
      <link>http://localhost:9393/blog/Dr+Strangelove.haml</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;22 Jan 2010&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://supak.com/store/videos/images/dr-strangelove.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do take a minute (or six) to watch this video on our knowledge of the known universe.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;object width=&quot;425&quot; height=&quot;344&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/17jymDn0W6U&amp;hl=en_US&amp;fs=1&amp;rel=0&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowscriptaccess&quot; value=&quot;always&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/17jymDn0W6U&amp;hl=en_US&amp;fs=1&amp;rel=0&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; allowscriptaccess=&quot;always&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; width=&quot;425&quot; height=&quot;344&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, &lt;br /&gt;
known universe = 13.7 billion light years. &lt;br /&gt;
Known planets harbouring intelligent life = 1 (earth). &lt;br /&gt;
Total nuclear megatonnage on planet earth = 5,000&lt;br /&gt;
Megatonnage required to destroy all life on Earth = 100 Megatons.&lt;br /&gt;
Number of times we can destroy the only planet within 13.7 billion light years which harbours intelligent life: 50.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we can do it in an afternoon. Toss in Murphy&amp;#8217;s Law and prepare for grandest folly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2010 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2010-01-22T12:00:00+05:30</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aamir Khan School of Acting.haml</title>
      <link>http://localhost:9393/blog/Aamir+Khan+School+of+Acting.haml</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;10 Jan 2010&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/aamir-khan-3-idiots-stills20.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Come, be an Idiot&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2010 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2010-01-10T12:00:00+05:30</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the Decade of the Proletarian.haml</title>
      <link>http://localhost:9393/blog/Welcome+to+the+Decade+of+the+Proletarian.haml</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;1 Jan 2010&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.pflp.ps/english/files/images/17.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This one is going to be nice. After the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2009/12/28/opinion/28krugman.html?_r=2&quot;&gt;great big zero&lt;/a&gt; that was the 00s, we find ourself at the threshold of a momentous decade. This is the decade where the proletarian voice finally gets heard in all its confusing babble, and a true consensus on the future of the planet will arise out of the tower of babel that is the competing conversations of humankind in the 21st century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A political system will arise that is more resembling natural &lt;a href=&quot;http://theautomaticearth.blogspot.com/2010/01/january-1-2010-fractal-adaptive-cycles.html&quot;&gt;adaptive systems&lt;/a&gt; with balance, sustainability, beauty and other such exalted notions as its cornerstones. Technology will make this possible. The world will rediscover and reinvent socialism and anarchy into a wonderful hybrid &amp;#8211; &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Panarchy&quot;&gt;Panarchy&lt;/a&gt;, along with open source government mechanisms which will soon wash away the blight of corruption, unequal power distribution and the overwhelming voice of corporate and capital power which dominates the airwaves today. The traditional structures are not so much under attack as being rendered obsolete, antiquated and unfit for the new world. It is a time of great promise and optimism for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are exciting efforts afoot. None of them make a direct and revolutionary assault on the ramparts of the state but that is going to be the nature of the revolution &amp;#8211; quiet, unassuming, unstoppable. Sites like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.myfootballclub.co.uk/&quot;&gt;My football Club&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slicethepie.com/&quot;&gt;Slice the Pie&lt;/a&gt; are the first voices in an inexorable movement towards proletarian rule. The revolution has never been so pure, so close and so tantalising as at this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding my voice to these conversations about who should rule and how this rule is to be exercised, I would like to humbly present &lt;a href=&quot;http://rbus.in&quot;&gt;rbus.in&lt;/a&gt;, a starting point for bringing about a panarchic public transport system in this blighted city we call home &amp;#8211; Mumbai. Rbus is open source, so feel free to start one in your city by forking it from its &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/svs/rbus&quot;&gt;github repository&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the way forward is not without its dangers. The traditional power structures are no strangers to the use of massive propaganda and violence to achieve their ends. When their propaganda starts failing, they will increase the intensity of their violence. The police state or military dictatorship (so beloved of some rightwingers in our nation) lurk on the horizon as dark possibilities, and the only thing that will keep them at bay is the shining light of information that is free. The most basic imperative of a proletarian today is to keep the lights on and the network up. The network is the basis of the peaceful revolution and protecting it is everyone&amp;#8217;s responsibility. The best way to protect the network is to use software that is free and accessibile to all. Do consider switching from your Windows or Mac machine to a Linux box. The new &lt;a href=&quot;http://ubuntu.com&quot;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt;, Fedora or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dedoimedo.com/computers/mandriva-2010.html&quot;&gt;Mandriva 2010&lt;/a&gt; are quite good choices to get started. Your digital freedoms are the basis on which you will operate in the new world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Money will disappear. Both of money&amp;#8217;s traditional roles as a medium of exchange and as a store of value are essentially forms of information storage. If this information can be stored in other places, such as in the community memory or in some database somewhere, then whether the Central Banks of the world like it or not, the monopoly on systems that aid exchange and store value is over and with it will end the edifice of the whole financial system &amp;#8212; of that &amp;#8220;giant squid wrapped around the face of humanity&amp;#8221; &amp;#8212; and all the unproductive activity that funnels power and pelf away from where it is created and into offices and boardrooms for a select few. The network will allow the cooperative management of more and more of the world&amp;#8217;s assets and will remove them from market mandated solutions. Things like education, healthcare, public transportation, arts and culture, environmental management and a whole host of other critical issues will be taken out of the sphere of the market and into the sphere of the commons, where they rightfully belong. Those enamoured of the new innovations of capitalism such as microfinance and affordable private schools will find that they have been mistaking capitalism&amp;#8217;s last, desperate and doomed attempt at credibility as its greatest success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have nothing but optimism for the future. I do hope we can all work together to make this decade one worth remembering for all the right reasons.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2010-01-01T12:00:00+05:30</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Avatar.haml</title>
      <link>http://localhost:9393/blog/Avatar.haml</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;22 Dec 2009&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;James Cameron knocks the ball out of the park&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.shockya.com/news/wp-content/uploads/avatar_james_cameron_guy.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
My God what a great film. Spectacular! With proletarian sympathies to boot.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2009 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2009-12-22T12:00:00+05:30</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bazaars, Freedom and Conversations.haml</title>
      <link>http://localhost:9393/blog/Bazaars%2C+Freedom+and+Conversations.haml</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;21 Dec 2009&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bazaarsconversationsfreedom.com/bazaars/&quot;&gt;Bazaars, Freedom and Conversation&lt;/a&gt; is the name of an awesome new book by Rajni Bakshi. The main theme of the book is an exploration of alternatives to conventional, growth based capitalism with its often brutal methods and neoclassical economics with its absurd constructs like homo economicus, etc. Rajni&amp;#8217;s task is to get the reader to stop treating capitalist dogma as a law of nature and to treat concepts such as money, the market and measures of value as changeable things, as matters of choice and things that can be shaped to suit the needs of the entire planet Earth, and not just those of a select minority of species homo sapiens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the book the reader is presented with facts that lie just outside the periphery of the capitalist gaze, such as the illuminating espousal of the rest of Adam Smith&amp;#8217;s work which shed a completely different light on his &amp;#8220;invisble hand&amp;#8221;. It seems that he never meant what they say he meant &amp;#8211; read the book for details. Not content with demolishing one of the cornerstones of market fundamentalist propaganda, she turns her gaze to various market failures, inequities, hypocrisies and patent brutality of a system that holds the absurd belief that profit is more important than people and that nobody owes anyone anything, that there is no such thing as society and that the natural world is an &amp;#8220;externality&amp;#8221; which need not enter into our calculation of cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While marking out a reasonably detailed map of the depletion of social capital, she also presents the too often untold and more often unheard stories of people seeking alternatives to the status quo. From the office of Richard Stallman &amp;#8212; founder of the Free Software Movement &amp;#8212; to the various attempts at alternative currencies and cooperative movements, the author makes the telling point that it is not true that greed and competition are the sole defining characteristics of humankind. She posits and provides ample evidence that sharing, cooperation and the desire for a more fulfilling spiritual existence are as natural impulses as the desire for a better material existence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The author is also quite nuanced in her approach to the market. She is not one to dismiss it as a barbaric relic of the past. Infact, she sees the bazaar as one of the defining characteristics of human society and celebrates economic freedom as another freedom for humans. What she laments is market fundamentalism, the intrusion of the market in places it doesn&amp;#8217;t belong, the suboptimal outcomes it produces and the conversion of the &amp;#8220;market economy&amp;#8221; into a &amp;#8220;market society&amp;#8221;. The author treats the bazaar as an important factor in providing a place for humans to gather, to exchange not just the produce of their labour but also to be together as social beings in a community gathering. It is the conversion of the bazaar into a &amp;#8220;market&amp;#8221; for the cold exchange of commodities that she disapproves of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the book is meant for a lay audience, there is no doubt as to the political sophistication of the author. She is one of the rare voices of humanity in a country ravaged by popular images of material success as the final goal of every activity, and the book represents a rare synthesis of many of the themes that have been troubling thinking people. The author&amp;#8217;s research is impeccable and the book is chock full of astonishing nuggets of information. To top it all off, it is very nicely written with wonderful stories to illuminate the points that the author is making.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, this book is highly recommended if you are feeling dissatisfied with the status quo and represents a very solid yet accessible starting point into left literature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More info &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.co.in/search?sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;amp;q=bazaar+conversations+freedom&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2009 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2009-12-21T12:00:00+05:30</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Time Magazine Loses It.haml</title>
      <link>http://localhost:9393/blog/Time+Magazine+Loses+It.haml</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;17 Dec 2009&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.zap2it.com/thedishrag/ben-bernanke-time-cover.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Wow, can you believe it? After Barack Obama talking war while receiving the Peace Prize, we get this &amp;#8211; Ben Bernanke is 2009&amp;#8217;s Person of the Year. I&amp;#8217;s over folks &amp;#8211; the Bilderberger Group now has complete control of the Earth&amp;#8217;s destiny and they just don&amp;#8217;t give a shit any more about the &amp;#8220;optics&amp;#8221; of what they do. It might seem as though the shadowy cartels that run the world are purposely trying to incite the people to violence, for whatever reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s an amazing quote from Time &amp;#8211; &amp;#8220;It is an independent government agency that conducts monetary policy&amp;#8221;. Hmm&amp;#8230;what is an independent government agency? One that is owned by the private banks it regulates? From Wikipedia -&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&amp;#8220;The Federal Reserve System is an independent government institution that has private aspects. The System is not a private organization and does not operate for the purpose of making a profit.&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn51&quot;&gt;51&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The stocks of the regional federal reserve banks are owned by the banks operating within that region and which are part of the system.&amp;#8221;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
It is so independent that no one has the authority to audit it? It is so independent that no one has the balls to shut it down. It is the master bank of all the banks and we know how unscrupulous banks can be. Ben Bernanke &amp;#8211; it must be nice to be chairman. All the dollars in the world, and Time magazine&amp;#8217;s award as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did someone notice that the American economy is F-U-C-K-E-D, and the whole world&amp;#8217;s financial system is on the verge of collapse and that managing these affairs is Ben Bernanke&amp;#8217;s job. Saying that it would have been much worse without him is akin to giving the captain of the Titanic an award for deploying the lifeboats. Errr&amp;#8230;a little perspective here guys? And what&amp;#8217;s next? Lloyd Blankfein for Pope?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, this is the end of the mass media. the proletarian&amp;#8217;s revulsion for this kind of self-aggrandising, quid-pro-quo, media-bank-corporate-politcs nexus is maxed out. Time to switch off the TV, burn the newspapers and start reading blogs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2009 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2009-12-17T12:00:00+05:30</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Decentralization.haml</title>
      <link>http://localhost:9393/blog/On+Decentralization.haml</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2 Dec 2009&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why States Are Getting Smaller In India&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.ecologyandsociety.org/vol9/iss1/art11/figure3.gif&quot; style=&quot;float:left;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;Of course, the reasons why states are getting smaller has nothing to do with foresightedness by the political class. It is purely symptomatic of the decentralisation of power going on everywhere, European Union not withstanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The decentralisation of power has its roots in the role of energy and information in the shaping of society. All society is shaped by its power structures, and power flows from only two sources &amp;#8211; access to energy and access to information. For millenia, when the access to energy was easier than the access to information (imagine a medieval European king who has access to a lot of farmland but no books or literate people), it was the access to energy resources that shaped society. However, there was always a class of merchants and scientists who made their living through the exchange and analysis of information. This is the class that broke the stranglehold of the clergy on people&amp;#8217;s minds and started a process of decentralising information, of which the Internet is today&amp;#8217;s manifestation. Today, information carries with it more transformational power than energy alone. Today, freelancers are able to perform collectively the jobs of organisations precisely because of the rapidity of information exchange as well as the presence of an information commons on the Internet. Thus empowered, they are changing the traditional roles of managers and organisations. This same process is at play everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not saying that the current demands for separate states are motivated by well informed people for the purpose of delivering justice. It is simply a symptom of this decentralising force that is in play today. Andhra politicians know that while the IT industry of the state is in Hyderabad, it is indeed possible to recreate the same conditions in Vizag, and this time they can get in the game earlier. The supremely critical strategic location of Hyderabad has been rendered irrelevant by the Internet. Hyderabad is a plum, but it is not the only one. This is just one possible explanation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Symptoms like the European Union may seem contrary to this trend, but taking away exchange rate risks on transactions between Germany and Belgium have massive effects when it comes to leveling the playing field for smaller businesses in Belgium in this example. It might seem like a Union, but it is de-centralising in its economic effects. AP and Telangana already share the same currency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Federal Model will not go away easily. An economically and politically weakened Center will push for either greater military strength or coercive police powers. This is the danger of Central mechanisms of coercion. States must take whatever measures appropriate to make sure that the coercive powers of the Center remain in check. Definitely desperate moves by the Center in India such as the talking up of Naxal menace, the deployment of the army and the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;UID&lt;/span&gt; scheme are all towards the same end. It is too late for the Center to impose &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;UID&lt;/span&gt;. This is not some &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;PAN&lt;/span&gt; number for 15 million odd people. We are talking about billions of people here. If the Center wants greater security and a &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;UID&lt;/span&gt;, it should educate the masses and let them loose on the Internet. They will create their own schemes of recognition and trust. A powerful central army deployed inside the borders of the Republic will be fatal to the long term viability of the Indian nation. Its existence will take on a logic of its own, until civil war becomes the norm. The drain on public resources and the distraction from the mission of educating, feeding and keeping the population happy will push Indian civilization below the critical level of intellectuals and scientists required to maintain a productive society. The middle class will become managerial serfs with exotic titles, mostly poor but with immense riches juuust out of their grasp. The rest of India will be available for resource plunder by the politcal classes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decentralisation is a powerful force, but it needs all the help it can get. Demand smaller and more accountable organs of government, starting from your local neighbourhood committee to Central government. Create decentralised power structures in your neighbourhood and in your city. Without these new power structures to balance out the immense capacity of violence that the Center can weild, things could get and continue to remain pretty ugly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2009 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2009-12-02T12:00:00+05:30</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Proletarian Blogging Engine.haml</title>
      <link>http://localhost:9393/blog/A+Proletarian+Blogging+Engine.haml</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;18 Nov 2009&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the heat of a winter Mumbai afternoon, the prole sits down to create a new blog engine? Why? Not just because he can but also because existing blog engines are too fancy. Not proletarian enough. Substance over form and all that. Armed with the ruby programming language and inspiration from projects like Tom Preston-Warner&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/mojombo/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, the prole decides he too would like to be like those cool kids who host their blog on github. Enter &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/svs/blu.rb&quot;&gt;blu.rb&lt;/a&gt;, the sinatra-based, minimal blog engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blu.rb (it&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;blurb&amp;#8221;, not &amp;#8220;blue dot aar bee&amp;#8221;) will publish any file under the views/posts directory in the blog index. Adding a .erb extension will give the post the layout in views/layout.rb (please read some Sinatra documentation. Blu.rb is simply a Sinatra app). Naming your post &lt;code&gt;My Post.layout_name.erb&lt;/code&gt; will apply the layout &lt;code&gt;views/posts/layouts/_layout_name.erb&lt;/code&gt;. Therefore, post names are not allowed to start with an underscore. However, all of these are defaults that can be fixed quite easily. Adding a config file might ease the situation but blu.rb is for hackers anyway. It is also trivially simple to use Haml instead of Erb. Blu.rb currently uses RedCloth to render textile syntax as html, so you can write beautiful, expressive text and have it rendered in style. It is of course, trivially simple to change the markdown language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With no file extension, you are free to provide any arbitrary html code. This will hopefully be helpful to designers and other cool people who craft blog posts not just with words but also with pictures and css. Of course, this means that adding disqus comments and closing html tags becomes your responsibility&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blu.rb also has the advantage of being a Sinatra app, so it gives you a wonderful api to add new routes and actions. Plugging in user authentication through &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/hassox/warden&quot;&gt;warden&lt;/a&gt; or advanced routing through &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/joshbuddy/usher&quot;&gt;usher&lt;/a&gt; are not problematic. In this case, blu.rb becomes the ideal blog engine for your cool new Rack based webapp as it can share rack login and session data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Installation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
$ git clone git://github.com/svs/blu.rb
$ cd blu.rb
$ ruby blu.rb # or check the config.ru for how to run it behind passenger&amp;lt;/pre&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding a post-commit hook to your blog repo on github to hit http://yoursite.com/update_blog will refresh the git repository in views/posts. Thus, simply commiting your blog repo will update your website. Blu.rb also publishes an &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/span&gt; feed at http://yoursite.com/feed. If you want to push directly from emacs, use &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/technomancy/magit&quot;&gt;magit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can check it out from here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/svs/blu.rb&quot;&gt;http://github.com/svs/blu.rb&lt;/a&gt;. For a sample blu.rb powered blog, you can check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/svs/blog&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2009 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2009-11-18T12:00:00+05:30</dc:date>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>